Arthur J. Cain Papers 1945-1988 Mss.Ms.Coll.63
American Philosophical Society
Arthur J. Cain Papers
1945-1988
Mss.Ms.Coll.63
American Philosophical Society
15.75 Linear feet
Arthur J. Cain is an evolutionary biologist whose research interests have included genetics, natural selection, biogeography, and systematics. Based at Oxford University and, later, the University of Liverpool, much of Cain's research was field-based, focusing on terrestrial gatsropods. This collection contains correspondence, grant applications, reports, programs for scientific meetings, unpublished papers and lectures, research notes, charts, graphs, maps, and manuscript reviews of journal articles and books. The Cain Papers is divided into three series: I. Correspondence; II. Subject Files; and, III. Papers by Colleagues. Arrangement is alphabetical by folder title, and chronological within each folder.
Cain, Arthur J. (Arthur James), 1921-1999
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Cain, Arthur James -- Conference on Population Studies of Polymorphic Snails Records (2 folders) 1966-1967
Cain, Arthur James -- Curriculum Vitae Manuscripts (14 pages) Circa 1975
Cain, Arthur James -- Ecological Genetics Group Records (7 items) 1967-1981
Cain, Arthur James -- Genetical Society Records (2 folders) 1979-1985
Cain, Arthur James -- International Conference on the Ecology and Genetics of Natural Snail Populations Records (1 folder) 1962
Cain, Arthur James -- Population Genetics Group Records (2 folders) 1967-1988
Huxley, Julian Correspondence (2 folders) 1956-1974
Krimbas, Costas B. Correspondence (21 items) 1977-1987
Lerner, Isadore Michael Correspondence (1 item) 1961
Lewontin, Richard Charles Correspondence (1 item) 1981
Mayr, Ernst Correspondence (3 folders) 1949-1986
Medawar, Peter Brian Correspondence (16 items) 1973-1984
Provine, William B. Correspondence (2 folders) 1984-1988
Sheppard, Philip M. Correspondence (3 folders) 1953-1980
Simpson, George Gaylord Correspondence (18 items) 1954-1984
Wright, Sewall Correspondence (2 items) 1970-1981
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Cain Papers were donated to the American Philosophical Society Library by Arthur James Cain in July, 1989. Their transfer from Liverpool, England, to Philadelphia was arranged by William B. Provine of Cornell University, in conjunction with the Philip M. Sheppard Papers (Ms. Coll. 65).
Scope and Contents note
The Arthur James Cain Papers (1945-1988) contain correspondence, grant applications, reports, programs for scientific meetings, unpublished papers and lectures, research notes, charts, graphs, maps, and manuscript reviews of journal articles and books. The bulk of the papers dates from the 1960s and 1970s, documenting the height of Cain's career as a biologist at the University of Liverpool. Some of the earliest items of the collection, ca. 1945-1946, are letters to Cain from English author and literary scholar, C. S. Lewis.
Series I. Correspondence, 1945-1988 25 boxes; 12.5 linear feet
Series II. Subject files, 1951-1988 5.5 boxes; 2.75 linear feet
Series III. Papers by colleagues, 1952-1980 0.5 box; 0.25 linear feet
Series I, II. Oversized materials 1 box; .25 linear feet
Materials filed in the oversize box follow the same alphabetical arrangement as Series I and II.
Cain's correspondence (Series I) represents the largest part of the collection, and contains some of the most noteworthy material. Letters discussing his research, expeditions, and data with fellow biologists are of particular interest. Research notes in the form of complete notebooks, per se, are not common; most of the pertinent information on Cain's research topics is dispersed throughout his correspondence with colleagues and in the miscellaneous documents filed in the subject files (Series II). The subject files also contain information regarding Cain's memberships and activities in biological societies and scientific organizations, and his Oxford University expeditions to the British Solomon Islands and British Guiana.
Biographical/Historical note
Arthur James Cain (1921-1999), Derby Professor of Zoology at the University of Liverpool, England, is renowned for his work in evolutionary biology and ecology. Cain's interests in natural selection, systematics, biogeography, and the history of biology are well documented in his many publications, but he is perhaps best known for his book, Animal species and their evolution (London, 1954), a survey of the nature of species, their origin, and their evolutionary importance.
Much of Cain's research focused on terrestrial gastropods, including snails and slugs, and particularly on the genus Cepaea, a group of land snails that exhibits tremendous variation in shell color and ornamentation, and which is thought to have been subject to strong natural selective pressure. The pattern of longitudinal banding in the shells of C. hortensis and C. nemoralis has been intensively studied by Cain and other geneticists, and Cain and his fellow Oxford biologist, Philip Sheppard, made important contributions to udnerstanding the genetic basis of ecophenotypic variation in the highly polymorphic C. nemoralis. Subsequent collaborative work with John Currey, combined with work on fossil gastropods, resulted in the discovery of the "area effects" phenomenon in Cepaea. Cain also made contributions to the systematics of oligochaete "worms" and birds such as fruit pigeons and parrots, and to avian biogeography.
Born on July 25, 1921, Arthur James Cain attended the Lawrence Sheriff School, Rugby, for his early education, and in 1939 was awarded an open scholarship (Demyship) to Magdalen College, Oxford, where he graduated with honors (first class) in zoology in 1941. Entering military service in December of 1941, Cain was commissioned Second Lieutenant in the Royal Army Ordnance Corps (R.A.O.C.- engineering) and was subsequently transferred to the Royal Electrical and Mechanical Engineers (R.E.M.E.) upon its formation. He was promoted to Captain in 1942.
After leaving the military in November, 1945, Cain immediately returned to Oxford to pursue a D.Phil. as an advanced student in the Department of Zoology. He easily matched his undergraduate successes in academics, becoming a Departmental Demonstrator in October, 1946, and receiving his M.A. in November, 1947. From January, 1949, until 1964, Cain was employed as University Demonstrator (now referred to as University Lecturer) in Animal Taxonomy, conducted research with John Baker, focusing on the histochemistry of lipids.
Cain's main interests, however, lay in evolutionary biology. From January to June, 1950, Cain studied with the great evolutionary biologist, Ernst Mayr at the American Museum of Natural History, New York, and took part in a scientific expedition to the Allegheny Mountains and Florida, the first in a long line of field expeditions in which he participated.
Leading an Oxford Department of Zoology expedition to the British Solomon Islands in 1953, Cain investigated the correlation between geographical, ecological, and morphological variation in birds, and his efforts helped earn his an appointment as Curator of the Zoological Collections at the Oxford University Museum in 1954, a position he held for ten years in addition to his duties as University Lecturer and as Lecturer in Zoology at St. Peter's Hall (1958-1961). In 1964, he left Oxford to become Professor of Zoology at the University of Manchester, and he later (1968) was appointed Derby Professor of Zoology at the University of Liverpool. He received emeritus status at Liverpool upon his retirement in 1989.
Cain's professional career was marked by a continued engagement in field research. As leader of the Oxford University expedition to British Guiana in 1959, he studied the comparative ecology of closely related species of birds in the tropical forest. In 1962, he was selected as the Oxford University representative on the Inter-Universities Committee for Research at Lake Kariba; and acted as the scientific secretary to this committee in the U.K. In this capacity, Cain made several trips to Africa from 1962-1965, conducting further research in Kariba and Johannesburg, and in 1965, he spent time at Serengeti National Park, Tanzania, studying avian ecology.
In his other professional activities, Cain served as editor of the Biological Series for Hutchinson's University Library from 1967-1975, as advisor in biology for the Science Research Council from 1972-1975, as well as remaining involved with many scientific organizations: as a founder and member of the Society for the Study of Human Biology, President of the Oxford Genetical Society, Zoological Secretary of the Systematics Association in Great Britain, member of the Council of the Linnean Society of London, fellow of the Institute of Biology in Great Britain, fellow of the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, member of the Malacological Society of London, and fellow of the Royal Society in Great Britain.
Cain died at home in Liverpool, England, in 1999.
Clarke, B. C. (Bryan C.); Cranach, Mario von, b. 1931; Davis, George Morgan; Mayr, Ernst, 1904-2005; Sheppard, P. M. (Philip Macdonald), 1921-1976; Woodruff, David S.; Biology; Biology--Classification; Birds.; Evolution (Biology); Gastropoda; Genetics; Maps; Mollusks; Natural selection; Ornithology; Paleontology; Pulmonata
- Series I. Correspondence, 1945-1988; 33 boxes; 16.25 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript, typescript, and carbon letters generated and collected by Cain throughout most of his career. Correspondence is almost entirely professional, with the exception of several letters written by his wife, J. T. Cain, during his 1953 expedition to the British Solomon Islands. The series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each file. When a correspondence file includes letters to a third party (i.e. not Cain), the name is indented on the next line.
  There are cross references for all third party correspondence.
  These files consist primarily of correspondence between Cain and his colleagues from the University of Liverpool and other academic institutions in Great Britain and abroad, and with students, publishers, editors, officers of professional societies, and admirers of his work in evolution, systematics, and genetics. In his correspondence, Cain frequently discusses his research, expeditions, grant applications, reviews of colleagues' journal articles and books, his own scientific publications, references for current and former students, requests for reprints, and invitations to attend and present papers at biological conferences and meetings.
  Cain's correspondence records his wide range of research interests in evolutionary biology, systematics, and genetics. His work on gastropods and other molluscs and on birds forms an important core of the Series. Among Cain's most frequent correspondents were Bryan C. Clarke, George Morgan Davis, Ernst Mayr, Philip M. Sheppard, Mario von Cranach, and David S. Woodruff. The correspondence file for Collins Publishers contains Cain's manuscript versions of chapters written for the Reader's Digest Book of British Birds, 1968. Other manuscripts of Cain's are lacking from the collection.
  For the most part, enclosures within letters have been retained with the original covering letter. Examples of such materials include unpublished scientific papers and articles, research notes, charts, graphs, maps, and forms for grant applications. Reprints, offprints, and photocopies of publications have been moved to the library's printed collections and are referenced in the card catalog under Cain's name. Photocopies of the title page of all transferred printed items have been filed with the original covering letter.
  - Abbott, Lois A., 1985 (Box Series I-1)
    Figure for Bisby, et al.
  - Abbott, Richard Tucker, 1976-1986; n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Acosta, Cándida R.T., 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Acuna, Luis Trevino, 1979-1980 (Box Series I-1)
    Mexico
    Naylor, E.
  - Adams, David, 1988 (Box Series I-1)
    Sec.-18th C. Society
  - Adams, Gabrielle, 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Michael, 1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Michael, 1976-1980 (Box Series I-1)
    Bryanston School
  - Agrawal, H.P., 1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aldridge, Tony, 1980 (Box Series I-1)
    Warden, Ainsdale
  - Alexander, Jason, 1981 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alexandrov, D.A., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
    Reprints
  - Al-Hassan, L.A.J., 1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allan, Andrian, 1987 (Box Series I-1)
    Assistant Archivist Liverpool Univ.
  - Allen, Clive, 1974 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, Fred, 1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, John A., 1972-1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alexander, E.E., 1964 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alonso, Teresa Aparicio, 1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ambrose, Anthony (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser.I, von Cranach, Mario
  - Anderson, Alph, 1977-1988 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, J.H., 1981 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, J.M., 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Anderson, William, 1982 (Box Series I-1)
    Nuffield Biology
  - Anderson, Wyatt W., 1983-1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - André, Joel, 1973-1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Angel, Martin V., 1959 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ansell, Alan D., 1986-1987 (Box Series I-1)
    Dunstaffnage
  - Answer, Peter, 1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Armengol, María F. López, 1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Armour, C.J., 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Armstrong, Roy, 1987 (Box Series I-1)
    Greenwood, J.J.D.
    Monaghan, Pat
  - Arnold, E.N., 1968-1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Arnold, Richard W., 1961-1975; n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Arockiam, J.P., 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Arthur, Wallace, 1975-1984 (Box Series I-1)
  - Asami, Takahiro, 1955-1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashcroft, D.L., 1976 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashmole, M. Philip, 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ashton, Peter S., 1973 (Box Series I-1)
  - Askew, R.R., 1964; 1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Atkinson, John R.E., 1971 (Box Series I-1)
  - Attenborough, David, 1979 (Box Series I-1)
  - Auber, L., 1968-1971 (Box Series I-1)
  - Auffenberg, Kurt, 1983-1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aurangzeb, R.P., 1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Austin, W.E., 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Avise, John, n.d. (Box Series I-1)
  - Axelrod, Daniel I., 1978-1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Backeljau, Thierry, 1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bailey, P.W., 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bailey, Stuart E.R., 1983-1988 (Box Series I-1)
    Guthrie, D.M.
  - Baird, Donald J., 1980 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bajema, Carl Jay, 1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Baker, John R., 1953-1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Baker, Sylva, 1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Balfour-Browne, Frank, 1964 (Box Series I-1)
  - Ball, Ian R., 1976-1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Balls, M., 1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bambach, R.K., 1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bancroft, J.D., 1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bantock, Cuillin, 1971-1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bar, Ze'ev, 1970-1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bareham, J.R., 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barker, David, 1952 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barker, Eileen, 1976-1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barker, G.M., 1976-1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barker, J.S.F., 1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barnard, Christopher, 1978-1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barnes, David J., 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barnes, Peter E., 1971 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barnes, S.E., 1960; 1962 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barnicot, Nigel A., 1970; 1973 (Box Series I-1)
  - Baron, P.J., 1976; 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barrett, H., 1964 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barrett, John, 1981-1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barrington, E.J.W., 1974 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bartholomew, M.J., 1976-1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - Barton, Nicholas H., 1979-1984 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bassett, Douglas A., 1983-1986 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bateman, Ken D., 1977-1978 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bateson, Patrick, 1983 (Box Series I-1)
  - Baur, Bruno, 1988 (Box Series I-1)
  - Baxendale, J.H., 1965 (Box Series I-1)
  - Bayliss, Charles E., 1965 (Box Series I-1)
  - Beard, Colin, 1974 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beardmore, John A., 1977; 1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beaumont, Andy R., 1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beaumont, Mark, 1984-1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beavan, John C., 1959 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beaver, Roger, 1980 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bebbington, Anne, 1980-1982 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beck, G.N.J., 1970-1971 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beck, J.R., 1959-1960 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beckett, Philip H.T., 1958-1959 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beetham, Paul A., 1976 (Box Series I-2)
  - Behnke, J.M., 1977 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bell, [?], 1955 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bell, Graham, 1978-1988 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bell, Richard H.V., 1964-1984; n.d. (Box Series I-2)
  - Bellamy, D., 1975 (Box Series I-2)
    -See also Ser.I, Creed, Edwin Robert
  - Benachenhou, Mourad, 1977-1978 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bengtson, Sven-Axel, 1977-1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bennet Clark, Henry, 1984 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bennett, Thomas Peter, 1976-1977 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bensusan, J., 1975 (Box Series I-2)
  - Berdoy, Manuel, n.d. (Box Series I-2)
  - Bergmans, Marc, 1987 (Box Series I-2)
  - Berry, R.J., 1968-1986; n.d. (Box Series I-2)
  - Betts, Heather R., 1985 (Box Series I-2)
  - Beu, Alan G., 1978-1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Billett, Frank, 1977-1980 (Box Series I-2)
  - Billington, W. David, 1971 (Box Series I-2)
  - Birch, Martin C., 1974-1983 (Box Series I-2)
  - Birkhead, Tim R., 1980-1987 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bisby, Frank A., 1975-1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bishop, Jim A., 1967-1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bishop, Martin, 1978-1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Blake, Gerald, 1958 (Box Series I-2)
  - Blaxter, John H.S., 1977 (Box Series I-2)
  - Blower, J. Gordon, 1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Blumenthal, Henry J., 1972 (Box Series I-2)
  - Board, Ron G., 1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Boettcher, Barry, 1983 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bogan, Arthur E., 1981-1988 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bond, G., 1963-1965 (Box Series I-2)
  - Boss, Kenneth J., 1968-1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Boussy, Ian A., 1983 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowden, John, 1966 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowden, K.F., 1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowden, S.R., 1979 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowers, Alan B., 1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowler, Peter R., 1983-1984 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bowsher, [?], 1973 (Box Series I-2)
  - Boyce, A.J., 1964-1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Boyden, Alan, 1971-1972 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brace, C. Loring, 1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brace, Robin C., 1978-1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bradbury, S., 1973 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bradley, J. Stuart, 1983-1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bradley, Martin, 1981 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bradshaw, A.D., 1987-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-2)
  - Bramah, Jean P., 1969-1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Bramwell, Andrew, 1973 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brand, A., 1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brande, Scott, 1978 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brasier, Martin D., 1978 (Box Series I-2)
  - Brimm, Robert M., 1981 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brent, Leslie, 1968 (Box Series I-3)
  - Broadhead, Edward, 1968; 1970 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brock, Jim, 1980 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brooks, Jane M., 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brower, Lincoln Pierson, 1975-1986; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Brown, Andrew Francis, 1983-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
    Brown, John D.
    Clark, George A.
  - Brown, D.H., 1974 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brown, E.S., 1955-1956 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brown, Edwina, 1974-1975 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brown, John D. (Box Series I-3)
    -See Ser.I, Brown, Andrew Francis
  - Brownbill, D., 1961 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brunet, Peter C.J., 1972-1975 (Box Series I-3)
  - Brussard, P.F., 1975 (Box Series I-3)
  - Bryson, Philip J., 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Buckley, John, 1970 (Box Series I-3)
  - Bull, C.M., 1981-1983 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burchnall, Herbert H., 1971-1981 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burfield, Diana, 1972 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burke, D. Patrick T., 1963-1984; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Burkhardt, Richard W., Jr., 1974-1975; 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burnet, Barrie, 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burns, John M., 1976-1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Bursell, E., 1966-1969 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burton, D.W., 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Burwood, H.W., 1958 (Box Series I-3)
  - Butler, G.W., 1963-1964 (Box Series I-3)
  - Butler, R., 1970-1975 (Box Series I-3)
  - Butler, Stella, 1978 (Box Series I-3)
  - Butt, Audrey, 1958 (Box Series I-3)
  - Butterworth, A.J., n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Byers, George W., 1964-1967 (Box Series I-3)
  - Cain, Joy T., 1953 (Box Series I-3)
  - Caligari, Peter D.S., 1977 (Box Series I-3)
  - Calow, Peter, 1974-1985; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Calver, Michael, 1985-1986; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Cameron, Douglas R., 1970 (Box Series I-3)
  - Cameron, Robert A.D., 1964-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-3)
  - Campbell, Robert, 1970-1984 (Box Series I-3)
  - Cannings, C., 1967-1968 (Box Series I-3)
  - Carey, J., 1970 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carrillo Barrios-Gómez, Enrique, 1983 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carrington, Richard, 1961-1964 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carter, D.J., 1971-1972 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carter, Edward C. II, 1985 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carter, G.B.M., 1975 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carter, Michael A., 1964-1985 (Box Series I-4)
  - Carthy, John D., 1965; 1971 (Box Series I-4)
  - Chance, Michael R.A. (Box Series I-4)
  - Charlesworth, Brian, 1980-1981 (Box Series I-4)
  - Charnov, Eric L., 1978-1979 (Box Series I-4)
  - Charreau, Ch., 1972 (Box Series I-4)
  - Chatfield, J.E., 1977 (Box Series I-4)
  - Cheke, Anthony, 1969 (Box Series I-4)
  - Chernov, Barry, 1986 (Box Series I-4)
  - Chevallier, H., 1971 (Box Series I-4)
  - Chichester, Lyle F., 1970 (Box Series I-4)
  - Christidis, Les, 1986 (Box Series I-4)
  - Christophers, Stuart C., 1972 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clapham, Christopher, 1962 (Box Series I-4)
  - Claridge, Michael F., 1959-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, B., 1969 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, George A. (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, George M., 1973 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, R.B., 1970-1975 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, S.R.L., 1986 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, W.A., 1975 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clark, Wilfred E. LeGros, 1964; n.d. (Box Series I-4)
  - Clarke, Bryan C, 3 folders (Box Series I-4)
    - Folder #1, 1964-1971 (Box Series I-4)
    - Folder #2, 1972-1987 (Box Series I-4)
    - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Series I-4)
  - Clarke, Cyril, 1976-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-4)
  - Clarke, Ian S., 1983 (Box Series I-4)
  - Clarkson, Keith, 1980 (Box Series I-5)
  - Clements, Geoffrey, 1985 (Box Series I-5)
  - Clutton-Brock, Tim H., 1982 (Box Series I-5)
  - Clyde, E., 1977 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coates, Catherine, 1975 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coe, Malcolm, 1971; n.d. (Box Series I-5)
  - Cohen, Mark, 1976-1977 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cole, Lionel, 1971 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coles, Brian, 1981 (Box Series I-5)
  - Collinge, Brian, 1979 (Box Series I-5)
  - Collins Publishers, 1961-1973 (Box Series I-5)
    Walter, Michael
  - Collinson, Richard I., 1971 (Box Series I-5)
  - Collyer, Garth P.V., 1962 (Box Series I-5)
  - Colville, Barry, 1977 (Box Series I-5)
  - Combs, V.A., 1975 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coney, Cliff, 1981 (Box Series I-5)
  - Conroy, Brian A., 1977-1983; n.d. (Box Series I-5)
  - Cook, Anthony, 1980-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-5)
  - Cook, D.G., 1975 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cook, Laurence M, 2 folders (Box Series I-5)
    - Folder #1, 1958-1976 (Box Series I-5)
    - Folder #2, 1977-1988; n.d. (Box Series I-5)
  - Cooke, F.P., 1979 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cooke, John A.L., 1969-1973 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coomans, H.E., 1978 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cootér, Jonathan, 1972 (Box Series I-5)
  - Copp, Charles J.T., 1976-1980 (Box Series I-5)
  - Copp. D.J.B., 1959-1974 (Box Series I-5)
  - Coppois, G., 1982-1983 (Box Series I-5)
  - Corliss, John O., 1970; 1973 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cornish, E.A., 1963 (Box Series I-5)
  - Costall, Alan, 1987 (Box Series I-5)
  - Courtney, Steve, 1979-1984 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cowan, M.B., 1965 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cowan, S.T., 1975-1976 (Box Series I-5)
  - Cowie, Robert Hulin, 2 folders (Box Series I-5)